<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Jackson Campolattaro</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Jackson Campolattaro</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 18:06:50 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>t-SNE</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/t-sne/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 18:06:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/t-sne/</guid><description>T-distributed Stochastic Neighbor Embedding (t-SNE) is a technique for visualizing high dimensional data in fewer dimensions while preserving clusters. Probabilities are computed for each pair of high dimensional data points being part of the same group, and then points are placed randomly in the lower dimensional space and their positions are iteratively improved until the difference between the probabilities in low and high dimensional space is minimized. By analogy, t-SNE minimization simulates forces between all data points, attracting similar points and repelling dissimilar points.</description></item><item><title>N-Body</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/n-body/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 15:06:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/n-body/</guid><description>N-Body is a personal project I started in the summer before my first year of university, in order to build familiarity with C++ in preparation for one of my year-1 courses. That preparation was ultimately redundant (it was an introductory course), but I enjoyed the work, and I&amp;rsquo;ve continued to add to the project during off periods, since.
The n-body problem is the algorithmic challenge of modeling the interactions between a very large number of point masses &amp;ndash; for example, when simulating the formation of galactic clusters.</description></item><item><title>Spectrogram</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/spectrogram/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 12:43:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/spectrogram/</guid><description>Spectrogram was a 4 month (one-semester) project completed as part of my coursework at Virginia Tech. The assignment allowed for a lot of leeway when selecting a task; because of my interest in music, I wanted to build a spectrogram (a type of audio visualizer). I formed a group with two like-minded students, and we set out with the goal of making a cross-platform C++ program which would visualize the system&amp;rsquo;s audio streams.</description></item><item><title>Quarter Id</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/quarter-id/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 11:25:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/quarter-id/</guid><description>Quarter ID was an 8-month (two-semester) project completed in my last year at Virginia Tech as part of the university&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;capstone&amp;rdquo; program. The goal of the project was to design and build a system which coin collectors could use to identify and evaluate the condition of washington quarters.
I was paired with three other students, two studying electrical engineering, and one studying computer vision. The first half of the project was focused around designing the hardware; because of Covid-19 I was the only student on campus, so I did most of the construction.</description></item></channel></rss>