<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jackson Campolattaro</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Jackson Campolattaro</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 20:18:06 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SIMD</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/employment/inria-simd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 20:12:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/employment/inria-simd/</guid><description>I enjoyed my time building an Octree for CGAL, and I was interested in continuing the same type of work. After the end of the summer I kept in touch with my mentor, and he put me in contact with his colleagues at Inria. Once I knew I would be attending graduate school in Europe we made arrangements for in-person work at Inria&amp;rsquo;s research campus in Sophia Antipolis, France.</description></item><item><title>Orthtree</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/employment/cgal-orthtree/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 10:28:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/employment/cgal-orthtree/</guid><description>Over the summer of 2020 I participated in Google&amp;rsquo;s Summer of Code program, which pairs students with open source projects. Because of my N-Body project I was familiar with tree-based algorithms, so I was drawn to CGAL&amp;rsquo;s proposed Octree project. I was paired with Simon Giraudot and worked remotely, corresponding by daily email and regular calls.
The boxes of an orthtree (black) produced by a point cloud (blue)
The goal of the project was to create a new CGAL package which provides an Octree data structure.</description></item><item><title>N-Body</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/n-body/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 15:06:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/n-body/</guid><description>N-Body is a personal project I started in the summer before my first year of university, in order to build familiarity with C++ in preparation for one of my year-1 courses. That preparation was ultimately redundant (it was an introductory course), but I enjoyed the work, and I&amp;rsquo;ve continued to add to the project during off periods, since.
The n-body problem is the algorithmic challenge of modeling the interactions between a very large number of point masses &amp;ndash; for example, when simulating the formation of galactic clusters.</description></item><item><title>Spectrogram</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/spectrogram/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 12:43:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/spectrogram/</guid><description>Spectrogram was a 4 month (one-semester) project completed as part of my coursework at Virginia Tech. The assignment allowed for a lot of leeway when selecting a task; because of my interest in music, I wanted to build a spectrogram (a type of audio visualizer). I formed a group with two like-minded students, and we set out with the goal of making a cross-platform C++ program which would visualize the system&amp;rsquo;s audio streams.</description></item><item><title>Quarter Id</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/quarter-id/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 11:25:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/projects/quarter-id/</guid><description>Quarter ID was an 8-month (two-semester) project completed in my last year at Virginia Tech as part of the university&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;capstone&amp;rdquo; program. The goal of the project was to design and build a system which coin collectors could use to identify and evaluate the condition of washington quarters.
I was paired with three other students, two studying electrical engineering, and one studying computer vision. The first half of the project was focused around designing the hardware; because of Covid-19 I was the only student on campus, so I did most of the construction.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 23:41:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Email j.campolattaro@student.tudelft.nl Github Linkedin</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 20:05:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m an American student earning my Masters in computer engineering at TU Delft. I&amp;rsquo;m currently seeking a software-focused thesis position in the Netherlands, with intentions to stay after my graduation.
Interests I&amp;rsquo;m drawn toward projects which involve:
Open Source Software High Performance Computing Multithreaded Programming (Homogeneous, Heterogeneous, and SIMD) Modeling and Simulation Hobbies Music The Apple music Favorites playlist is usually representative of the types of music I&amp;rsquo;m listening to at the moment.</description></item><item><title>Inria SIMD Blog</title><link>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/employment/inria-simd-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 15:59:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://jacksoncampolattaro.github.io/employment/inria-simd-blog/</guid><description>Note: This page is mirrored from my page on CGAL's internal wiki, apologies for any incorrect formatting. Contents 1 Introduction 2 Project Goals 2.1 Minimum Viable Product 2.2 Stretch Goals 3 Timeline 3.1 Now - June 7 3.2 June 7 - June 21 3.3 June 21 - July 7 3.4 July 7 - July 21 3.5 July 21 - August 7 3.6 August 7 - August 14 4 Progress 4.</description></item></channel></rss>